JIESHAN CHEN

Address: Level 5/13 Garden St, Eveleigh NSW 2015, Australia.

Gender: Female

Phone: (+61) 452 234 123 Email: Jieshan.Chen@data61.csiro.au Website: https://chenjshnn.github.io/

RESEARCH INTEREST

My work lies in the fields of software engineering, deep learning, and human-computer interaction. My research focus on guaranteeing and supporting responsible software development by design using AI/ML techniques. Specifically, my research includes examining and mitigating accessibility and ethical issues in apps and enhancing the productivity during software development using responsible AI techniques. Total Citation: 837.

EDUCATION

Australian National University

August 2018 – December 2022

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Thesis: Improving the Efficiency of Mobile User Interface Development through Semantic and Data-Driven Analyses Supervisors: Zhenchang Xing and Chunyang Chen

Sun Yat-Sen University

August 2014 – June 2018

Bachelor in Statistics, School of Mathematics

Honors Graduate

Overall GPA: 3.8/4.0 (89/100)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

CSIRO's Data61, Australia

January 2022- Present

Research Scientist – Software Engineering for AI (SE4AI) Team

- Lead of sub-team UI intelligence in SE4AI Team (3 research scientists, 1 senior engineer, 1 engineer, 1 Postdoc, 3 PhD students)
- Lead Immersive AI cluster initiatives at Data61

Apple Inc., USA (Remotely from Australia due to Covid)

March 2021 – September 2021

AI/ML Research Intern - Machine Learning + UI Understanding Team

Project Topic: Enhancing the accessibility for screen readers and mobile users (finished two papers, one accepted at CHI'22 [C.4, O.2])

HONORS & AWARDS

CSIRO SCS Biannual Awards – Early Career in Science Award	June 2024
CSIRO SCS Biannual Awards - Women in Science Career Award	June 2023
ACM SIGSOFT Distinguished Paper Award in ICSE 2020	July 2020
Google PhD Fellowship Nomination	2020
ANU HDR Fee Remission Merit Scholarship	2018-2022
ANU Ph.D. Scholarship (International) Full-Time	2018-2021
Honors Graduate of Sun Yat-Sen University	June 2018

PEER-REVIEWED CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS – Research/Technical Track

[C. 9] GPTVoiceTasker: Advancing Multi-step Mobile Task Efficiency Through Dynamic Interface Exploration and Learning

Minh Duc Vu, Han Wang, Jieshan Chen, Zhuang Li, Shengdong Zhao, Zhenchang Xing, Chunyang Chen *Proceedings of the ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST 2024)*Core Ranking **A***, To appear

[C. 8] Where is it? Tracing the Vulnerability-relevant Files from Vulnerability Reports

Jiamou Sun, <u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Zhenchang Xing, Qinghua Lu, Xiwei Xu, Liming Zhu Proceedings of the ACM/IEEE International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE 2024) Core Ranking **A***

[C. 7] Is It a Trap? A Large-scale Empirical Study And Comprehensive Assessment of Online Automated Privacy Policy Generators for Mobile Apps

Shidong Pan, Dawen Zhang, Mark Staples, Zhenchang Xing, <u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Xiwei Xu, and Thong Hoang Proceedings of the USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX 2024)

Core Ranking **A***

[C. 6] Unveiling the Tricks: Automated Detection of Dark Patterns in Mobile Applications

<u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Jiamou Sun, Sidong Feng, Zhenchang Xing, Qinghua Lu, Xiwei Xu, Chunyang Chen *Proceedings of the ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST 2023)* Core Ranking **A***, Acceptance Rate 25% (121/483)

[C. 5] Let's Chat to Find the APIs: Connecting Human, LLM and Knowledge Graph through AI Chain

Qing Huang, Zhenyu Wan, Zhenchang Xing, Changjing Wang, <u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Xiwei Xu, Qinghua Lu *Proceedings of the IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering (ASE 2023)* Core Ranking **A***, Acceptance Rate 20.3% (134/661)

[C. 4] Towards Complete Icon Labeling in Mobile Applications

<u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Amanda Swearngin, Jason Wu, Titus Barik, Jeffrey Nichols and Xiaoyi Zhang. *Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI 2022)* Core Ranking **A***, Cite 16, **Acceptance Rate 12.5%** (324/2,597)

[C. 3] Object Detection for Graphical User Interface: Old Fashioned or Deep Learning or a Combination?

<u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Mulong Xie, Zhenchang Xing, Chunyang Chen, Xiwei Xu, Liming Zhu and Guoqiang Li. Proceedings of the ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (ESEC/FSE 2020)

Core Ranking A*, Cite 117, Acceptance Rate 28% (101/360)

[C. 2] Unblind Your Apps: Predicting Natural-Language Labels for Mobile GUI Components by Deep Learning.

<u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Chunyang Chen, Zhenchang Xing, Xiwei Xu, Liming Zhu, Guoqiang Li, and Jinshui Wang. *Proceedings of the ACM/IEEE International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE 2020)* Core Ranking **A***, Cite **111**, Acceptance Rate 20.9% (129/617)

ACM SIGSOFT Distinguished Paper Award

[C. 1] Ensemble Application of Convolutional and Recurrent Neural Networks for Multi-label Text Categorization.

Guibin Chen, Deheng Ye, Zhenchang Xing, <u>Jieshan Chen</u>, and Erik Cambria.

Proceedings of the IEEE International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN 2017)

Core Ranking A, Cite 290

PEER-REVIEWED JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

[J. 4] Let's Discover More API Relations: A Large Language Model-based AI Chain for Unsupervised API Relation Inference

Qing Huang, Yanbang Sun, Zhenchang Xing, Yuanlong Cao, <u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Xiwei Xu, Huan Jin, Jiaxing Lu ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (TOSEM2024), To appear

[J. 3] Revealing the Unseen: AI Chain on LLMs for Predicting Implicit Data Flows to Generate Data Flow Graphs in Dynamically-Typed Code

Qing Huang, Zhiwen Luo, Zhenchang Xing, Jinshan Zeng, <u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Xiwei Xu, Yong Chen ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (TOSEM2024), To appear

[J. 2] Prompt Sapper: A LLM-Empowered Production Tool for Building AI Chains

Yu Cheng, <u>Jieshan Chen*</u>, Qing Huang, Zhenchang Xing, Xiwei Xu, Qinghua Lu ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (TOSEM2024), Cite 7

[J. 1] Wireframe-based UI Design Search through Image Autoencoder.

<u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Chunyang Chen, Zhenchang Xing, Xin Xia, Liming Zhu, John Grundy, and Jinshui Wang. ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology Volume 29 Issue 3 Article No.: 19 pp 1–31 (TOSEM 2020)

Core Ranking A*, Impact Factor: 2.674, Cite 78

OTHER PUBLICATIONS

[O. 5] The Invisible Game on the Internet: A Case Study of Decoding Deceptive Patterns

Zewei Shi, Ruoxi Sun, <u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Jiamou Sun, Minhui Xue The Web Conference 2024 (WWW2024) - Short Papers Track Core Ranking **A***

[O. 4] Designing with Language: Wireframing UI Design Intent with Generative Large Language Models

Sidong Feng, Mingyue Yuan, <u>Jieshan Che</u>n, Zhenchang Xing, Chunyang Chen arXiv preprint arXiv:2312.07755

[O. 3] Towards Real Smart Apps: Investigating Human-AI Interactions in Smartphone On-Device AI Apps

Jason Ching Yuen Siu, <u>Jieshan Chen*</u>, Yujin Huang, Zhenchang Xing, Chunyang Chen arXiv preprint arXiv:2307.00756

[O. 2] Extracting Replayable Interactions from Videos of Mobile App Usage

<u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Amanda Swearngin, Jason Wu, Titus Barik, Jeffrey Nichols and Xiaoyi Zhang. arXiv preprint arXiv:2207.04165

[O. 1] UIED: A Hybrid Tool for GUI Element Detection

Mulong Xie, Sidong Feng, Zhenchang Xing, <u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Chunyang Chen

Proceedings of the ACM Joint Meeting on European Software Engineering Conference and

Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering – Companion (ESEC/FSE 2020 - Tool Demo)

Cite 57

* means corresponding authors

IMPACTFUL TOOL AND WORK

UIED (User Interface Element Detection) http://www.uied.online/

- Total Citation:174, GitHub Stars: 336, Fork: 98
- Integrated into an industrial testing tool, VTest, for daily testing of a dozen popular industrial apps, such as
 Taobao in Alibaba, a highly popular ecommerce app in China, with about <u>one billion monthly active users</u>,
 Alipay, a highly popular payment app with <u>over one billion users</u> and Software Green Alliance to provide testing services for top smartphone vendors and app vendors in China.

Enhancing the accessibility for screen readers and mobile users

• Published two papers on this topic, one of them is awards SIGSOFT Distinguished Paper Award (C.2)

Incorporated to <u>iOS'14 as a new feature</u> named "screen recognition" which significantly improves the
accessibility of previously inaccessible apps from operating system level.

MENTORSHIP

PhD Student

- (2024 Present, CSIRO's Data61 & UniMelb) Zewei Shi
- (2024 Present, CSIRO's Data61 & ANU) Zeyu Zhang
- (2023 Present, CSIRO's Data61 & UNSW) Mingyue Yuan

Visiting PhD Student

- (2024 Present, Tianjin University) Sai Zhang
- (Upcoming, NTNU) Andre Storhaug

Research Engineer

• (2023 – Present, CSIRO's Data61) Dustin Minh Duc Vu

Master/Bachelor students - final year project

- (2023 Jiangxi Normal University) Yu Cheng [J.2]
- (2023 UNSW) Wenbo Zou
- (2023 Monash) Ziqi Zhao
- (2022 Monash) Jason Ching Yuen Siu [O.3]
- (2020-2021 ANU) Xincheng Xu, Yukang Liu
- (2019-2020 ANU) Zhaowen Xu, Kexin Zhang, Mulong Xie [C.3, O.1]
- (2018-2019 ANU) Kai Xi

Research Courses

 (2023 Monash – FIT 4701) Alex Zhou, Sam Howard, Nobert Bayer, Yicheng Peng, Prithviram Prabhuram, Chen Liu

SERVICE

Chair

• ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS'24 – LAMPS Workshop)

Program Committee

- International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE'25)
- ACM SIGSOFT International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis (ISSTA'24)
- IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering (ASE'23, ASE'24, ASE'25 Artifact Evaluation)
- IEEE International Conference on Software Analysis, Evolution and Reengineering (SANER'24 ERA Track)
- ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (ESEC/FSE 2023-SRC Track)
- ACM international joint conference on pervasive and ubiquitous computing (UbiComp/ISWC'23 Posters and Demos)
- International Conference on Software and System Processes (ICSSP'23)
- IEEE International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE'22- Industry Track)
- ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI'22-Computational UI Workshop)
- The Mining Software Repositories (MSR'22-Shadow PC, MSE'23-Junior PC)

Reviewer

- ACM Transaction on Computer-Human Interaction (TOCHI)
- IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (TOSEM)
- ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST'22, UIST'24)

- ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI'22, CHI'23, CHI'24)
- ACM SIGCHI Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work & Social Computing (CSCW '24)
- IEEE Conference on Virtual Reality and 3D User Interfaces (IEEE VR'23)
- The Mining Software Repositories (MSR'22, MSR'23)
- ACM international joint conference on pervasive and ubiquitous computing (UbiComp'22)
- International Journal of Human-Computer Interaction (IJHCI'22)
- IEEE International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE'22)
- IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering (TSE'22, TSE '23)
- Information and Software Technology (IST Journal'21)